A Guide to the Byron Nelson Cooper Papers, 1925-1971
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series I. Subject Files, 1925-1971
  - "The University and the Learning Process," n.d. (Box-folder 6-5)
  - University of North Carolina, 1962 (Box-folder 6-6)
  - Untitled speech, 1964 (Box-folder 6-7)
  - "Vertical stylolites," n.d. (Box-folder 6-8)
  - Virginia Academy of Science, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 6-9)
  - Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station, 1954 (Box-folder 6-10)
  - Virginia Association of Professional Geologists, 1961-1963, n.d. (Box-folder 6-11)
  - Virginia Coal and Iron Company, 1961-1962, n.d. (Box-folder 6-12)
  - Virginia Coal and Iron Company, 1963-1968, n.d. (Box-folder 6-13)
  - Virginia Dunbrick Company, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 6-14)
  - Virginia Iron Coal and Coke Company - drill log, 1968 (Box-folder 6-15)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1953-1970 (Box-folder 6-16)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute Department of Geological Sciences, 1948-1971, n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 6-17)
  - Virginian Limestone Corporation, 1954-1968 (Box-folder 6-18)
  - "Virginia's Outdoor Laboratory," n.d. (Box-folder 6-19)
  - Ward, L. E. Jr. 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6-20)
  - Ward's Natural Science Establishment, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 6-21)
  - Water analysis reports, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 6-22)
  - Water laws and agencies (Virginia), 1964-1965, n.d. (Box-folder 6-23)
  - Water Resources Research Institute, 1964-1965, n.d. (Box-folder 6-24)
  - Water well recommendations and specifications, n.d. (Box-folder 6-25)
  - Weller, Marvin, 1945-1947, n.d. (Box-folder 6-26)
  - "When Was the Holston Mountain-Iron Mountain Thrust Formed?" n.d. (Box-folder 6-27)
  - "Whiskey for the Cat," n.d. (Box-folder 6-28)
  - Wiley and Wilson, 1958-1970, n.d. (Box-folder 6-29)
  - Woodbridge Clay Products, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 6-30)
  - Wytheville Formation lithologic variations diagram, n.d. (Box-folder 6-31)
  - Zinc and lead resources of southwestern Virginia, n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 6-32)
- Series II. Photographs and Negatives, 1953-ca. 1970
  - Aerial photographs, 1953-1954, n.d. (Box-folder 6-33)
  - Aragonite crystal negatives, n.d. (Box-folder 6-34)
  - Caliente Range - Carrizo Plains photographs, n.d. (Box-folder 6-35)
  - Cedar Grove photographs and negatives, n.d. (Box-folder 6-36)
  - Gatewood Dam and stream gage stations photographs, n.d. (Box-folder 6-37)
  - Geological samples - one-second exposure negatives, n.d. (Box-folder 6-38)
  - Geological samples negatives, n.d. (Box-folder 6-39)
  - Klotz Quarry photographs, n.d. (Box-folder 6-40)
  - Paleo report negatives, 1954 (Box-folder 6-41)
  - Paleo report negatives (Moore), 1955 (Box-folder 6-42)
  - Paleo report negatives (Steele), 1955 (Box-folder 6-43)
  - Paleo report negatives, 1956 (Box-folder 6-44)
  - Paleo report negatives, n.d. (Box-folder 6-45)
  - Smyth County geology and field camp photographs and negatives, n.d. (Box-folder 6-46)
  - Virginia Fisheries Laboratory, n.d. (Box-folder 6-47)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute Department of Geological Sciences (rocks, camps, field trips, etc.) negatives, n.d. (Box-folder 6-48)
  - Western United States negatives, n.d. (Box-folder 6-49)
  - Miscellaneous photographs and negatives, 1954-ca. 1970, n.d. (Box-folder 6-50)
    - Geology awards and Mrs. Davis, 1956
    - Zone 1 Yorktown fossils, n.d.
    - Unidentified woman (probably Elizabeth Cooper) on farm, n.d.
    - Faculty and students using laboratory equipment, n.d.
    - Unidentified specimens, n.d.
    - North Fork of Holston River, 1954
    - Carolina gneiss -Transylvania County, North Carolina, n.d.
    - Spruce Run Mountain, n.d.
    - Boulder on Salt Pond Mountain, n.d.
    - Shale near Princeton Gate, n.d.
    - St. Clair fault - near Narrows, Virginia, n.d.
    - Unidentified man preparing rock samples, n.d.
    - Railway tunnel [probably Montgomery, Virginia], n.d.
    - Cooper with students at granite quarry in Mt. Airy, North Carolina, ca. 1970
    - Unidentified rock outcroppings, n.d.
    - Unidentified bridge, n.d.
    - Aerial view of North Carolina Granite Corporation quarry, n.d.
    - Drilling rig, n.d.
    - Unidentified student organization, n.d.
  - Unidentified 16mm short films, n.d.